You will register for marriage tomorrow?
明天就登记
Yes.
嗯
Tomorrow at noon.
明天中午
The two of us
我们俩
will take the afternoon off for it.
请了下午的假去领证
Getting married
这结婚
is not the same as dating.
跟谈恋爱可不一样
You should really
你们还是应该
think it over carefully.
慎重考虑一下吧
Do you
你
really know him well?
了解他吗
I do.
了解
Mom,
妈
don't you know him well too?
你不是也挺了解他的吗
He is the nephew of Mr Wu,
他就是你要给我介绍的
whom you wanna introduce to me.
吴老师的外甥
He has good looks,
相貌端正
clean family background,
家境清白
and excellent character and abilities.
人品能力样样拔尖
You said with his situation,
你还说就这品相
he has no match
在相亲市场
in the dating market,
可以以一敌五
and if I nailed him,
我要是把他
and brought him home,
领回家的话
I wouldn't wanna go on blind dates anymore.
以后再也不想相亲了
Did you forget all that?
忘了
Honestly,
咱们家呀
we don't oppose flash marriage.
倒是不反对闪婚
But there should be
但毕竟
some emotional foundation, right?
也得有点感情基础吧
Sir, ma'am,
叔叔阿姨
we do have
我跟筱柠
such a
确实有一定的
foundation.
感情基础
We're classmates back in high school.
我们俩是高中同学
We've known each other for about 10 years.
认识差不多快十年了
There's something
有件事呢
I haven't told you two.
我也一直没跟你们俩说
Actually,
其实
I've had a crush on him for ten years.
我暗恋他十年了
I've been having feelings for him
从高中的时候
since high school.
就一直喜欢他
But he's way out of my league,
不过他太优秀了
so I didn't have the courage to confess.
我就没好意思表白
[When I met him during our blind date,]
相亲的时候遇见他了
[I felt that besides him,]
我就觉得除了他
[I wouldn't take anyone else.]
别人谁都不行
[We decided]
我们俩决定了
not to waste time
不浪费光阴
and go straight to the point.
直接一步到位
[Mom,]
妈
[dad,]
爸
give me the household registration.
把户口本给我吧
Besides, I'm getting married,
再说了我结婚
aren't you both happy?
你们俩不也高兴吗
Then I won't have to keep urging
我就不用老催着
you two
让你们俩
to set me up on blind dates.
给我介绍对象了
Yuheng,
小纪
what do you think?
你怎么想
I truly
叔叔阿姨
want to
我是真心想要
marry Xiaoning.
跟筱柠结婚
So please,
所以叔叔阿姨
you can trust me with her.
可以放心地把她交给我
OK.
行
We have no objections.
我们俩没什么意见
You two decide for yourselves.
你们自己决定吧
Ms Rao, there's a
静姐
document that needs your signature.
有份文件需要你签字
Is there anything else?
还有事吗
Once I finish my work,
我忙完工作
can I take
下午能不能
3 hours off this afternoon?
请三个小时的假啊
Sure.
可以
Thank you.
谢谢静姐
Ms Rao, I'll be off then.
静姐我先走了
OK.
好
Goodbye, Mr Zhao.
走了赵经理
See ya.
拜拜 拜拜
What's going on with her?
小涂这是怎么了
Why in such a hurry?
急成这样
Going to get married or something?
赶着结婚去啊
Did you bring your stuff?
东西带了吗
What about yours?
你的呢
Then let's...
那我们就
Roll!
出发
Hello.
您好
We'd like to register for marriage.
我们办一下结婚证
Please take a number first.
那边自助机先取个号
Then go over there to wait.
然后去那边等待办理
OK.
好
Thank you.
谢谢
Hello.
您好
Here are our documents.
这是我们的材料
What about the photo?
照片呢
I need it.
照片也得给我
Photo?
照片
Sorry about that.
不好意思啊
We decided to get married on a whim,
我们是临时决定结婚的
so we didn't take any photos.
没有拍照片
You can take next door.
出门右转可以拍照
Make it fast.
快一点
We are about to close.
我们要下班了
Thank you.
谢谢
OK.
行
Give me the stuff.
东西您给我
Here.
给
Thank you.
谢谢
Run.
跑两步
They are about to get off work soon.
他们马上要下班了
Hurry up. Hurry.
快点 快点
Quick.
快
Get closer.
头靠近一点
More.
靠近一点
You two are newlyweds.
你们俩是新婚夫妻
[Why are you being so polite?]
这怎么谦让的
[You're acting like moral exemplars.]
跟道德标兵似的
[Think about your past]
想想你们过去
[sweet days.]
甜蜜的日子
[Today, you finally reap the rewards.]
今天终于修成正果了
[How happy!]
多开心
[So sweet!]
多甜蜜啊
[OK, come on.]
好 来
[Let's do it again.]
咱们再来啊
[Get ready!]
准备
If you really can't do it,
你俩要实在不行
just go outside and gather your emotions.
就出去酝酿一下情绪
I have a line of people waiting outside.
我外面排着队呢
No please.
不行
We are also in a hurry.
我们俩也挺赶时间的
Sorry about that.
不好意思啊
This is our first marriage,
我们俩第一次结婚
and we have no experience.
没什么经验
Is my smile not good?
我笑得不好吗
It's quite good.
挺好的
How about
要不这样
considering this
咱们就想成
something for the annual meeting?
行里年会的时候拍照
OK.
好
Let's try again.
我们再试试
Alright.
行
OK then.
好嘞
Get ready.
准备
3,
三
2,
二
1, go!
一
For marriage registration,
你说领证
should we also pick an
是不是也要找一个
auspicious day?
黄道吉日啊
Rushing and hurrying,
紧赶慢赶地
we still didn't make it.
还是没赶上
It's alright.
没关系
We took the photos anyway.
反正照片也拍了
Next week, let's find a time
下周咱们找个时间
to come and get it.
过来领也一样
OK.
嗯
Let's go.
走吧
Have some tea.
喝点茶
Thanks.
谢谢 谢谢
My husband just brought it back.
这都老涂新拿回来的茶
Good.
好 好 好
Thank you.
谢谢
Here.
来
OK.
好
Hey, you're back.
回来了
Welcome back!
回来啦
How did it go?
怎么样顺利不顺利
I posted about you getting married
我呀把你们领证的事
in our family group chat.
发到咱们家大群里了
Everyone came over to celebrate.
大家都过来热闹热闹
Thank you.
谢谢大姨
So this is your son-in-law?
这就是咱家女婿呗
So cool!
好帅呀
When you have your wedding,
结婚的时候
don't forget us old neighbors.
别忘了我们这些老邻居
We'd like to give you wedding gift money.
我们也要来随份子的
Where's your certificate?
结婚证呢
Show it to us!
拿出来给我们看看呀
Let us share the joy.
让我们也沾沾喜气
Yeah.
对
Let's see it.
拿出来看看
I left it in the car.
忘车上了
Another time.
改天
We'll show you some other time.
改天拿出来给大家分享
That's good.
好 好 好
Have some fruit.
吃 吃水果
Come on, sit.
坐 坐 坐
Then you two...
那你们
Go inside and get cleaned up.
进屋收拾 收拾
Sit down.
坐啊
Sit.
坐呀
You see.
我看
We have so many relatives here.
外面亲戚那么多
My mom is also in high spirits.
我妈也正在兴头上
How about we don't mention
要不领证的事
the certificate for now?
就先别说了
Don't spoil her mood.
别扫她的兴
We'll get it done next week after all.
反正下周也领到证了
We can show it
不行到时候领完了
to them then.
再给爸妈看也一样
So when do you
那你下周
have time next week?
什么时候有时间
I'll ask for leave in advance.
我提前请好假
In the first two days,
下周前两天
I have an audit inspection
我有一个审计检查
meeting to attend.
总结会要开
It's really hard to take leave.
确实不好请假
How about Wednesday?
要不周三
OK.
好
Yuheng,
小纪
since you've already registered,
既然你们已经领证了
let's arrange a time later
那回头安排个时间
to meet with
我们跟亲家
your parents.
见个面
Sir, ma'am,
没问题叔叔阿姨
I'll arrange it as soon as possible.
我尽快安排
Why are you still calling us that?
怎么还叫叔叔阿姨呢
Exactly.
就是
We are a family now.
这都一家人了
You'll have to
你早晚
change how you address us.
你得改这个口
You might as well do it now,
你还不如就现在
while the mood is right.
趁这个热乎劲
Right?
是吧
No rush, right?
不着急吧
How about we just
等 到时候
wait until the wedding?
举办婚礼的时候再改呗
Sure.
行啊
Dad.
爸
Mom.
妈
Don't worry,
你们放心
I'll take good care of Xiaoning.
我一定会照顾好筱柠的
Come on!
快 快 快
Here.
来
Address change fee.
改口费
Thank you, dad.
谢谢爸
You both
一人一个 一人一个
have it.
一人一个
Thank you, dad.
谢谢爸
I wish you happiness and fulfillment
妈妈祝你们幸福美满
together until old age.
白头到老
I wish you're both...
爸祝你们 早
um...
早
happy day and night.
早晚都幸福
Day and night?
什么早晚幸福
How about at noon?
中午就不幸福了
You should say happy all day!
每天都幸福
Dad.
爸
What are you so happy about?
您这看什么呢这么开心
I just like to see
我就喜欢看
the two of them
她们母女俩
sitting there like that.
那么坐在那儿
It makes me happy.
我看着就开心
In the future,
以后啊
in your marriage life,
你们婚后啊
as you live together,
生活久了
you will naturally understand
你自然而然就知道
that nothing
什么
is better than being a family,
都不如一家人
spending time together.
平平安安地待在一起
Yes.
是
That is true happiness.
那才叫幸福呢
In your days ahead,
你俩结婚以后啊
make sure to get along.
好好相处
Do you know how to cherish your wife?
知道怎么疼老婆不
First of all,
首先呢
you need to be attentive.
你得细心
Keep in your heart
筱柠喜欢什么
what Xiaoning likes
不喜欢什么
and doesn't like.
你得记住了
And you
其次呢
need to love her with all your heart.
你得用心
Got it.
是
Women,
这个女人哪
whether young
不管是年轻的
or old,
还是年老的
love to be romantic.
就喜欢浪漫
To be romantic?
浪漫
Basic necessities are essential.
柴米油盐是基础
About being romantic,
浪漫 这根弦
you need to keep that in mind.
你得绷紧喽
What's the key?
最重要的呢
A woman can skip a meal.
女人哪可以一顿饭不吃
But
但是
if you miss out on a surprise
假如你错过一次
that should have been there,
应该有的惊喜
then you're done for.
那你就完了
Got it.
知道了
Yuheng is an
小纪这个孩子
attentive and patient guy.
细心又耐心
You have good taste in choosing a husband.
你选老公的眼光不错啊
You're as good as I.
跟我不分伯仲
You've only met him twice.
你才见他两面
And you're praising him
就把他夸得
like he's the best in the world.
天上有地下无的
What's going on?
怎么了
What happened to your picky standards?
您以前那些挑剔标准呢
He is so measured in his actions.
他做事这么有分寸
What's not to praise about?
还不让人夸呀
Do you know him well?
你 跟他熟吗
How do you know he is measured?
你怎么知道他有分寸啊
I just know.
反正我就是知道
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒
For what?
谢我什么
For cooperating with me
谢谢你配合我
to deal with the relatives and parents.
搞定亲戚和爸妈
If it weren't for you today
要不是你今天
playing along with me,
跟我打配合
if I suddenly told them
我突然跟他们说
that I was getting married,
我要结婚了
I bet their blood pressure and heart rate
估计他们的血压心率
would have skyrocketed.
都会上去了吧
Since it's a real marriage,
那既然是真的结婚
I still need to show proper etiquette.
该有的礼数还是要有的
For all possible future situations
以后你有什么没想到的
or things you need to do,
没做到的
I'll take care of them for you.
我都替你想了
OK.
好
Why do you smile?
笑什么
Nothing.
没什么
I just
我就是
suddenly feel
突然感觉
like there's really
真的有一种
a sense of being about to get married.
准婚后的意思了
Isn't it
难道不是
the feeling of married life?
婚后生活的感觉吗
Then,
那
what should we do tonight?
咱们今晚怎么安排呀
My parents think
我爸妈他们
that we are already married...
觉得我们俩已经结婚了
I'll follow your lead.
我都听你的
I just feel that right now,
我就是觉得现在
the transition of my role is too fast.
这个角色转换得太快了
I'm not ready yet.
我还没有准备好
So...
所以
I completely understand.
我特别理解
No one can change
不会有人能转变
that fast.
那么快的
How about
那要不这样
I go home tonight?
我呢今天先回家
You can spend more time
你回去之后
with your parents.
陪陪叔叔阿姨
OK.
好
Nope, our parents.
陪陪爸妈
Once we adapt to our new roles,
等适应了新的身份
we will see how it goes.
我们再从长计议
OK.
好
Get home safe.
那你 路上慢点开车
Let me know when you arrive.
到家了跟我说一声
Sure.
好
I'll see you getting inside.
我看你回去
See ya.
拜拜
Come on.
来吧
[Pick one.]
选一套
[We've got to meet a client tonight.]
晚上跟我去见个客户
Meet a client?
见客户啊
You don't want to?
不方便啊
No.
没有
Back when you
你以前
were working in the lobby,
在大堂工作的时候呢
your work was
你的工作
usually done within
是在八个小时之内
eight hours.
开展的
But in the BDD,
但是在拓展部工作
what you do outside
八个小时以外
of those eight hours
你做了什么
is what matters most.
才是最重要的
In here,
在拓展部工作
you won't have the luxury
没有你在大堂工作
of enjoying a comfortable life.
安享晚年的好命
You need to have the courage
那你就要有披荆斩棘
to forge ahead.
拓展前路的勇气
These outfits
这些衣服呢
are not shortcuts for you,
也都不是你的捷径
but just your battle attire.
只是你去战场的战衣
Whether you go to battle or not,
但是最终上不上战场
the decision is yours.
决定权在你
Of course, I'm going.
当然要上战场了
So tonight,
那晚上是不是
are we going to drink?
要喝酒啊静姐
Are you OK with that?
能喝吗
Yes.
能
Very good.
非常好
Remember to
记得把那个头发
let down your hair.
放下来啊
That way goes better with this dress.
跟这条裙子更搭
OK.
好
[Let's have dinner together after work.]
下班一起吃饭吧
I don't have time tonight.
今儿晚上没时间
Hi, Mr Yao.
姚主任
Mr Ji.
纪老师
Come on,
来 来 来
get in.
快进来
Please.
您请
Let's go.
走吧
[Ms Rao.]
饶经理
[Is there a business dinner?]
这是有饭局啊
[Yeah.]
对
[Good.]
好啊
[You refused my dinner invitation]
拒绝我的晚餐邀请
[just to attend a business dinner?]
就是要去参加饭局
[No wonder your department]
难怪你们拓展部
[is always full of vitality.]
总是充满了生机
[Mr Yao...]
姚主任
[The after-work life of employees]
打工人的下班生活
[doesn't really belong to them.]
本来也不都属于自己
[It's earned through hard work.]
真枪实弹干出来的
So,
所以呢
I hope you
我希望姚主任
won't believe
不要听信外界
those rumors.
那些谣传
I also hope
也希望
that the Compliance Dept
咱们这个合规部啊
could go easy
对于我们拓展部
on us.
能高抬贵手
About the rumors, whether true or not,
这传言真实与否
we will take it seriously.
我们合规部自会判断
However, if there are some
不过若是有一些
borderline behaviors,
界限边缘的行径
which may seem legal now,
目前看似不违法
[it doesn't mean they are compliant.]
但不代表合乎规则
Please keep this in mind, Ms Rao.
还请饶经理能够谨记
Mr Ji,
纪老师
are you warning me now?
您现在是在给我警告吗
Just a friendly reminder.
温馨提示
I will keep it in mind.
我谨记在心
[See you.]
回见
Did I just
我刚
offend him or something?
哪儿得罪他了吗
Did he eat dynamites for lunch?
吃炸药了
Mr Ji,
纪老师
why haven't you left yet?
你怎么还没走啊
We are off now.
现在是下班时间
You can stop calling me that.
可以不要叫我纪老师
Where are you eating tonight?
晚上去哪儿吃
At Nanzhi Restaurant.
南枝餐厅
Ms Rao will be here soon.
一会儿静姐要过来了
You have to drive there?
还要开车去啊
Aren't you going to drink?
不是要喝酒吗
Ms Rao said to call a designated driver.
静姐说叫代驾
If you don't want to go,
你要是不想去的话
I'll help you
告诉我
out of this.
我帮你
No, I want.
我想去
I'm different now.
我现在不一样了
Before, in the lobby,
以前在大堂
I observed carefully and was approachable,
我细心观察热心亲民
and that's enough to solve problems.
就可以解决问题
Now I have to go to the battlefield.
我现在是要上战场的
You seem to be quite untroubled.
你倒是 挺不挣扎
I have to.
挣扎有什么用啊
Struggling is just depleting myself.
挣扎就是内耗
It's better to just do it.
还不如先做
If I can't make it,
实在不行
I can always retreat.
我再当逃兵呗
Why did you just
你刚才为什么
say those to Ms Rao?
对静姐那样啊
Because she
因为她
ruined our
破坏了我们的
first dinner.
第一次晚餐
You always manage to separate work and life.
你不是公私不分的人
Since when did you
什么时候对我
understand me so well?
这么了解了
I've seen Mr Ji at work.
纪老师工作的状态
I know it well.
我可是见过的
Rao Jing likes to
饶静这个人做事情
overstep boundaries.
喜欢踩界
I was just giving some advice.
我只是给了一些忠告
As long as it doesn't concern me.
不是因为我就好
Here.
拿着
I'm going.
我走了
Be safe.
注意安全啊
Don't worry, I've got this.
放心吧 没问题
[Mr Qian.]
钱总
[This wine]
这款
is from northern Portugal.
来自葡萄牙北部的红酒
The vintage is just right.
年份正相当
I toast to you,
我敬您
hoping you can give us
希望您给我们代瑞一个
an opportunity
可以跟您一起
to develop the southern market together.
开拓南方市场的机会
This winery
这个酒庄
is not well-known.
知道的人很少啊
You must have done
看来你一定是
your research.
做了功课的
Rao Jing,
饶静
the ones working under you
你带的人
are indeed promising.
果然是孺子可教啊
Mr Qian,
钱总
rookies
这新人吧
need to learn.
她就得多学习
They've got to memorize a lot.
多记多背
You often interact with banks,
不像您跟银行打交道多
and you're almost a pro at it.
都快成半个专业人士了
In the future,
以后我们小涂啊
you'll see Xiaoning very often.
您还得多指教指教
Cheers!
来
[Qian Dong, 43 years old.]
钱冬四十三岁
He took over the family mining business.
接任家族矿产
In just six years,
仅六年的时间
he
就
had tripled the business
让家族矿产的业务量
volume.
翻了三番
He has high standards for life,
平时对生活有要求
and has a good relationship with his wife.
跟妻子的感情很好
His son studies abroad.
儿子在国外读书
He enjoys niche Portuguese wine.
喜欢喝葡萄牙小众红酒
He aims at the southern market,
因为要开拓南方市场
So, many banks
所以很多家银行
are eager to give him loans.
都想接手他的贷款业务
Xiaoning,
小涂
if you like wine,
你喜欢红酒
we should share more insights.
咱们以后可以多交流
Who knows,
说不定咱们
we might even become friends.
还可以成为朋友
That would be my honor.
那是我的荣幸
But honestly,
不过说实话
I don't know
我对红酒
much about wine.
其实不是很了解
It's because I was providing
是因为我给
loan consulting to
之前的一个客户
a previous client and
做贷款咨询的时候
he shared with me the info about the wine.
那个客户跟我分享的
He happened to
正好他跟您一样
also enjoy red wine
也喜欢来自葡萄牙
from northern Portugal,
北部的红酒
especially from Porto.
尤其是波尔图
He just returned from the UK
刚从英国回来
and is planning to invest in mining.
也准备投资矿产
You two might actually know each other.
说不定您二位还认识呢
Is that guy named
这个人是不是叫
Qian Junsheng?
钱俊生
Yes.
对呀
I thought you might know him.
我就说你们可能认识
Xiaoning!
小涂
We can't disclose client information.
客户信息我们不便透露
Did he get a loan
他是从你们代瑞
from you?
贷款了吗
Mr Qian,
钱总
I apologize for that.
实在是不好意思啊
Xiaoning is new here
小涂是新人
and doesn't know the rules yet.
不懂什么规矩
And she also isn't aware
而且她也不知道
of
您跟
your relationship with him.
他的关系
As a rookie,
新人吗
that's understandable.
可以理解
So, you need to guide her properly.
所以要好好教
Please rest assured,
钱总您放心
I'll make sure to do that moving forward.
我以后一定好好教
It's Xiaoning's mistake.
今天是我们小涂的错
How about
您看这样
I toast you with three glasses
我先 敬您三杯
to express our apologies?
替她赔个不是
Open the compartment.
把那边打开
There's another document inside.
里面还有一份资料
Regarding the interest rates,
贷款的利率呢
they're all quite similar.
都大同小异
So think carefully
所以你好好想一下
about how to convince Mr Qian
怎么能让钱总
that he should choose
非我们代瑞不可的原因
us at Dairui.
是什么
Also,
还有啊
after reviewing the document,
看完资料以后
highlight the main points.
摘出重点
Later, think about how
待会儿想想办法
to communicate
在饭桌上
this information to Mr Qian
怎么把这些消息
during dinner.
传达给钱总
Got it.
好
So, what's the
那这个事儿
current status of this matter?
进行到什么程度了
As long as there's an exclusivity agreement,
只要有这个排他协议呢
Dairui won't work with
我们代瑞是不可能
anyone you disapprove of.
跟您介意的人合作的
Also, your contracts with Visi Bank
而且您与维西银行
for other projects
其他项目的合同
are still valid.
也没有到期
I believe Visi Bank
我相信维西银行
would not easily
也不可能因为一个
give up on
其他人
such a valuable client like you
而放弃您这么一个
just because of someone else, right?
大的客户是不是
So,
所以呢
as long as there's no support
只要没有
from these two banks,
这两家银行的支持
even if some people are very capable,
就算是某些人再有本事
they won't make much of an impact.
也翻不出什么浪花的
Ms Rao,
静姐
take it easy.
少喝点
I can handle it.
我来喝
Show me the contract, please.
把合同拿过来我看一下
Do you have a girlfriend now?
是不是有女朋友了
I know you well.
我可了解你啊
You never check your phone
你在外边
when you're out.
可从来不看手机的
Between us,
咱们师徒之间
there shouldn't be any secrets.
可别藏着掖着
Alright?
听见没有
It seems nothing
还真是什么事儿
can escape your notice, sir.
都逃不过老师您的眼睛
Yes, I do have a girlfriend.
确实是有女朋友了
When did this happen?
什么时候的事儿
After all these years,
这么多年
I've never noticed
我可从来没发现
any girl around you.
你身边有过女孩
It's a recent development.
就是最近的事
When I get the chance,
等有机会了
I'll bring her
我带她
to visit you.
过去拜访您
Good, good.
好 好 好
Sir,
老师
you called me over for tea today.
您今天喊我过来喝茶
Is there something on your mind?
是有什么心事吗
You know,
可能你也知道
the BDD has been
最近拓展部
facing a lot of issues lately.
出了很多事儿
The section one led by Mr Jiang
老江带队的一部
ran into some trouble.
出了岔子
Xing Yu from the section two
二部的小邢呢
is overly ambitious.
野心又太大
He's always
他呢
thinking about
总想着
merging the two sections.
把两个部门合并了
But I know his capabilities.
但他的能力我知道
Such merge
真要合并那拓展部
would be chaotic.
还不得乱了套了
The two sections
这一部跟二部
handle most of the loan business
承担了行里的大部分
in the bank.
贷款的业务
Chaos must not happen.
确实不能乱
Exactly.
对呀
Let's not dwell on this anymore.
不提了 不说这事
It's not easy to ask you out
好不容易约你出来
for tea.
喝个茶
How is your mom doing lately?
你妈最近身体怎么样
She's doing well.
她还好
She must
听说你
have been overjoyed to know
有女朋友了是不是
that you have a girlfriend.
高兴坏了
I told her right away.
第一时间就跟她说了
You should have.
应该的
Ms Rao, are you alright?
姐你没事吧
Did I cause you trouble?
我是不是闯祸了
You had to drink that much.
害你喝这么多酒
It's fine.
没事
You did great.
你做得挺好的
Usually, Mr Qian
平时那个钱总呢
is hard to approach.
总是油盐不进的
I've thought of many strategies
我想了很多办法
but couldn't win him over.
都拿不下他
Until I heard that
直到我听说
his father's youngest son
他父亲的小儿子
returned to China,
回国以后
and was doing some loans
在对一些小的银行
with some smaller banks.
做一些贷款
He wants to get involved in
想做一些
the mining sector.
矿业方面的事情
I realized this
我就知道这个
would definitely be the breakthrough.
一定是他的突破口
But this is also
但同时这个也是
a sensitive issue for him.
他的雷点
Not something to tread on lightly.
绝对不是随便能踩的
So if you were the one
所以 这事要是
who mentions this,
由你说出来的话
he might feel threatened,
他觉得你在威胁他
which would backfire, right?
反而适得其反了是吧
Otherwise, why do you think
那不然你觉得
I had you dress so nicely
今天咱能出来吃这个饭
for the dinner tonight,
我让你穿这么好看
what was it for?
为了什么
To sell your looks?
出卖色相吗
I just want you to
我只不过想让你
play the role of a naive rookie at work
扮演好一个职场愣头青
and then casually
然后在不经意之间
pass this information to him.
把这个消息传递给他
Got it?
明白吗
Yeah.
明白了
So he wouldn't think
那他不会觉得
we were colluding, right?
是咱们俩串通的吧
Some people,
有一些人呢
when they are
对一些事情
well-versed in certain matters,
深谙此道的时候
tend to become complacent.
就会自我麻痹
He believes
他觉得
he's quite adept at
他对于我们销售的伎俩
our sales tactics.
驾轻就熟
So today,
所以你今天
by overly dressing up
用力过度地穿着
and showcasing this drinking culture,
还有背的这个酒桌文化
he thinks
让他认为
you're just a rookie.
你是一个职场小白
In this way,
这样呢
whatever actions you take
你做出什么样的事
or clients you attract,
拉什么样的客户
would all seem reasonable.
就都合理了
So those 3 glasses of wine
那刚才那三杯酒
should have been my responsibility.
应该我来喝的
You shouldn't make a habit
挡酒的事情
of drinking in my stead.
下不为例
You'll need to meet clients
你以后总要
on your own in the future, right?
自己见客户的吧
Ms Rao,
姐
you don't need to do it. I'm a drinker.
你不用帮我挡酒我能喝
Really?
是吗
Yes, really.
真的
Alright.
行
Let me see how well you can drink.
让我看看多能喝
Ms Rao.
姐
OK, OK.
好
You're amazing.
你好棒
You did great today too.
你今天也很棒
You're truly a drinker.
你真的很能喝
How come you're so good at it?
你怎么这么厉害
Why isn't there a driver available?
怎么没有代驾接单啊
Just wait
再等一下
a moment.
再等一下啊
Why isn't there a designated driver?
这附近怎么没有代驾呀
Ms Rao...
静姐
Mr Ji,
纪老师
what are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿
I was passing by for work.
我正好有工作路过的
Did you drink?
喝酒了
Just a little bit.
喝了点
At this hour,
这个时间呢
it's hard to find a driver.
不太好叫代驾
Let me give you a ride.
我送你们吧
The car is here?
车来了
Yes, it's here.
车 来了
- OK. - The car is here.
也行 车来了
Then please help me with her.
那麻烦您帮我扶一下
I'm OK on my own.
不用我自己来
I can handle it myself.
我自己来
I...
那我
The shotgun.
副驾吧
OK.
好
Ms Rao,
饶经理
she seems to have a moderate tolerance.
这同事看起来酒量一般
She's had quite a bit, right?
喝了不少吧
You're referring to
纪老师是说
Xiaoning, right?
小涂吧
She really has had a lot tonight.
她今天晚上确实没少喝
A lot indeed.
没少喝
The rumors seem to be true.
看来传言说得还挺真实
I'm not sure what rumors
我不知道纪老师
you have heard,
听到什么传言
but I know
但是我也知道
that I do have
我饶静确实
some info circulating.
在外面有一些传言
But these
但是这些呢
are all my personal actions.
都是我的个人行为
I don't want
我也不希望
the entire section one
我们拓展一部
to take the blame for me.
替我来背这个黑锅
But so you know,
可是我想跟纪老师说
some people,
就有些人吧
and some matters,
还有些事
require time to settle
它是需要时间的沉淀
to be truly understood.
才能明白的
Moreover, I have my principles
而且我饶静做事呢
in my work.
是有底线的
I do hope so.
希望是这样
Some people,
有些人就是
even if you've known them for long,
认识了很长时间吧
you still don't really understand them.
你却一点都不了解他
While some,
那有些人呢
you just met,
你刚认识
but feel very familiar with.
就觉得很熟悉
Who are you referring to?
说谁呢这是
My boyfriend, maybe?
男朋友吧
Yeah,
对
I should call him that.
我应该这么叫他
Xiaoning.
筱柠
We're home.
到家了
Come on, put on a jacket.
来 披件外套
Careful, your purse.
小心啊 包
Come on.
来
Watch your step.
小心 看脚下
Take it slow.
慢点啊
Be careful.
小心
We'll be home soon.
坚持一下马上到家了
Is the key in your purse?
钥匙在包里吗
I'm not sure.
不知道
How could you leave without the key?
出门怎么也没带钥匙
Dad.
爸
Mom.
妈
[Yuheng.]
小纪
Hi, mom.
喂 妈
Are you and dad not home?
您和爸没在家吗
[We're in the countryside.]
我们来乡下
[At your aunt's house.]
你大表姨家了
[What's going on?]
怎么了
You're not coming back tonight?
今天晚上不回来了呀
[Your uncle will drive us]
晚上你大姨父开车
[back tonight.]
送我们回去
[Is there something you need?]
有什么事儿吗
I'm taking Xiaoning home.
我送筱柠回家
She forgot her keys.
她没带钥匙
[She forgot her keys?]
没带钥匙啊
[Then she can just stay at your place.]
那就回你们家去住呗
[You're married now.]
都结婚了
[You should have your own home.]
该有自己的小家了
[Xiaoning]
筱柠
[might be too shy]
是不是不好意思
[to bring this up.]
跟我们提呀
[We're not that narrow-minded.]
我们哪有那么不开明啊
[After we get back,]
回去以后呢
[we'll bring her stuff]
我们把她的行李
[over to you.]
给你送过去啊
Alright.
行
Take care,
那您和爸回来的时候
and have a safe trip back.
注意安全啊
We'll head back.
我们先回了
[OK.]
好
[Drive safe.]
你们也注意安全啊
Come on.
来
Be careful.
小心点啊
This way.
这边儿
Come on.
来
[Door's open.]
已开锁
Be careful.
小心啊
Slowly.
慢点
Where are we?
这是哪儿呀
This is my...
这是我
This is our home.
这是我们的家
Our home.
我们的家
It smells minty.
薄荷味
It's your scent.
是你的味道
Let's go.
走
I'll help you over to sleep.
我先扶你过去休息
Sit for a while.
坐一会儿
Come on.
来
Slowly.
慢点
I haven't drunk too much.
我没喝多
Be careful.
小心
I can walk by myself.
我可以自己走
Come on, slowly.
来 慢点啊
We're home.
回家了
It's great to be home.
回家了真好
Just wear these slippers for now.
你先穿这双拖鞋
They're my mom's.
我妈妈的
I'll go to the grocery store later
一会儿去超市
and buy you a new pair.
我再给你买双新的
No, no.
不用 不用
What a waste!
浪费
No need for that.
不用
But Rao Jing...
这饶静也是
How much did she make you drink?
让你喝了多少酒
The rules in your department
这拓展部的规矩
really need to change.
真该改改了
Don't talk about her like that.
不许说她
She is very good.
我们饶经理可厉害了
Took you out for drinks
带你出去喝酒
and didn't even take good care of you,
也不说好好照顾一下
a little girl.
你这个小朋友
I'm not a little girl.
我不是小朋友
I'm almost getting married.
我都快结婚了
It's hot.
热
So hot.
好热
It's burning hot!
我说 我说我热
You look good.
真好看
I've been meaning to tell you,
我一直没好意思告诉你
actually, you fit
其实你都长在了
my aesthetic perfectly.
我的审美点上
Your eyes are beautiful.
眼睛好看
Your nose is beautiful.
鼻子好看
Your mouth is beautiful too.
嘴巴也这么好看
Everything about you is beautiful.
哪儿都好看
If it weren't for the fact that you
要不是因为你
are so good-looking,
长得这么好看
how could I possibly
又怎么可能
agree to marry you on a whim?
一下子就答应结婚的呀
Don't you think I'm superficial.
你不许觉得我肤浅啊
Get handsy again, I'll...
下次要是再敢动手动脚
[Yuheng.]
昱恒
[I heard there's a new drug abroad]
我听说国外新出一款药
[that's very helpful for your mom.]
对阿姨的病情很有帮助
[But it's not cheap.]
就是价格不便宜
[You should be prepared.]
你做好准备啊
[Thanks.]
谢谢啊
[Is all of this]
这一切
[really happening?]
是真的吗
What is this place?
这哪儿呀
[These boxes are from mom and dad.]
这几个箱子是爸妈
[They were delivered yesterday.]
昨天同城闪送来的
[The pajamas]
睡衣
[were put on by yourself.]
是你自己换的
[The toiletries are in the bathroom.]
洗漱用品都在卫生间
[There's breakfast on the table.]
桌子上有早餐
[The keys to the house are next to it.]
旁边是家里的钥匙
[Lastly,]
最后
[this is my home.]
这是我家
[And also,]
也是
[our home.]
我们的家
[Ji Yuheng.]
纪昱恒
Mr Jiang was fired.
老江被开除了
Back to your work.
回去吧
Mr Zhao.
赵经理
Isn't it a bit early?
早了点吧
Mr Jiang's sensitive about his pride.
老江这人好面子
Zhou Kai is someone
周凯又是
he trained himself.
他一手带出来的
He's being dirty
手脚不干净
is like staining Mr Jiang's reputation.
就是在打他的脸
He was fired because of this.
他就因为这事被开除了
So who will be in the charge
那咱们部门
of our department from now on?
以后谁说了算啊
I heard a new one is coming.
据说有新的领导要来
They'll also merge us with section two.
还要把咱们跟二部合并
Merging?
跟老邢合并
And they're bringing in
还要来一个
a new guy.
不熟悉的空降兵
What a disaster!
这还让不让人活了
Zhao Nan!
赵楠
What brings you here?
你怎么过来了
Xiaoning.
筱柠姐
I'm here to drop off some files.
我来拓展部送份材料
I miss you so much!
好久没见我都想你了
How about
怎么样今天中午
having lunch in here today?
要不要在这儿吃个饭呀
It's on me.
我请客
I'd like to check out the cafeteria here.
尝尝你们这儿食堂
You're really trying
怎么那么会
to save money for me. Let's go!
替我省钱呀 走
Xiaoning,
筱柠姐
how's the new department treating you?
你去新部门怎么样啊
It's alright, I suppose.
还行吧
Here,
给你看
these are some new photos I took.
这是我新拍的照片
We went out for ice cream.
我们去吃冰激凌
Oh, sorry.
不好意思
No worries.
没关系
I want a bit of everything.
每样都要一点
Done.
好了啊
I'd like some of those.
阿姨我要这个
Xiaoning,
筱柠姐坐呀
have a sit.
快点我们吃饭
OK.
好
Mr Ji,
纪老师
what's with the
脖子上的划痕
scratch on your neck?
怎么回事啊
Do you have a girlfriend now?
是不是有女朋友了
Sir, ma'am.
叔叔阿姨
Here are all my documents.
这是我全部的证件
The property deed, diplomas,
有房本 学历证明
a criminal record check,
无犯罪证明
a credit report,
征信记录
and my bank statements
以及最近几年的
for recent years.
存款明细
I realize this
我知道这种方式
might seem a bit inappropriate,
可能有些欠妥当
but it's the fastest way
但是这是我能想到的
I could think of
最快速地让两位
to help you both get to know me.
能够了解我的方式了
This is quite thorough.
这是准备得还挺全的
Well,
这样
please take a seat.
你先坐吧
Have a sit.
坐 坐 坐
Okay.
好
Actually, I've known Xiaoning
其实我跟筱柠
for quite a while, not just recently.
不是最近才刚认识的
We're classmates in high school.
我们是高中同学
It's a
这次呢
reunion after a long time.
是久别重逢了
You knew each other in high school?
你们高中就认识了
Yes.
对
Please take a look at this.
叔叔阿姨您看
This umbrella
这把伞
should look familiar, right?
应该还有印象吧
This is my company's umbrella.
这 这我们单位的伞
This is...
这不
How come...
你怎么
Back then,
那个时候
I went through a particularly helpless
我有一段特别无助
and lost time.
也特别失落的时间
This umbrella
这把伞
was a gift from Xiaoning.
是筱柠她送给我的
She gave me a lot of hope.
她给了我很多希望
I've cherished it all this time.
我一直都珍藏着它
So you're saying
你的意思是说
that after all these years,
这么多年了
you haven't forgotten her?
你都没有忘记她
Then why are you only mentioning it now?
那怎么现在才说呢
Xiaoning had
筱柠她之前
a boyfriend before.
一直都不是单身
And I just
而且我也是
returned from abroad.
刚刚从国外回来
The most important thing is
最重要的一点
I know she has been going on
我知道她最近这段时间
blind dates frequently lately.
开始频繁相亲了
So after all these years,
那你这么多年的心思
does Xiaoning know how you feel?
筱柠她知道吗
I didn't tell her.
我是没有告诉她
I was afraid it would scare her.
怕吓到她
I just told her
我只是跟她说
that I wanna get married
我想结婚
to settle down.
是为了先稳定下来
Yuheng,
小纪
I have a question.
我有一个问题
When you proposed to her,
你跟我们家筱柠求婚
did she
她
say yes to you?
答应了吗
She's
筱柠她
still considering it.
确实还在考虑
To be honest,
说实话
your qualifications
你的条件呢
surely exceed
那肯定是超过了
most parents'
大多数父母的
criteria for a son-in-law.
择婿标准了
However,
但是
that doesn't include us.
并不包括我们
Right?
对吧
Exactly.
没错
Xiaoning is our daughter,
筱柠是我们的女儿
but she is also
但是她更是一个
an independent person.
独立的个体
We respect all her decisions,
我们尊重她所有的决定
especially her choice
包括婚姻
of marriage.
尤其是婚姻
Her preferences
她的喜好
are our
就是我们
top priority.
最大的选择标准
If she chose you,
如果她选择了你
our entire family
我们全家
would wholeheartedly accept you.
肯定是衷心接纳的
But if not,
但如果她拒绝了你
don't you think you can find a workaround
你也别想通过这种方式
through this method.
曲线救国
We will never force her
我们是绝对不会强迫她
to do something she doesn't want.
做自己不喜欢的事情
Yes. That's right.
对 对 对
Do you
你
understand?
明白了吗
Yes,
嗯
I understand.
我明白